Kierra Dahlin

Ph: 780-263-7389

Email: <u>kaovelson@shaw.ca</u>
Westlock, AB

Focus

Artistic and communication skills have always come naturally for me. The eagerness and desire to create, whether illustrations or building 3D models by hand was something that was never really taught, but was encouraged my entire life. Receiving training at NAIT in the Digital Media and IT program harnessed those natural abilities, while giving guidance in basic design and coding practices. Though at first a learning curve, through hardwork and determination to do well, this course ultimately helped me grow as a designer, coder, and a communicator.

My focus is to use the knowledge I gained from NAIT, including: attention to detail, best coding practices, website layouts, and creative solutions. Through work and personal experience I have improved greatly in working with Adobe programs, WordPress, refining my illustrations, and working to achieve clear communication with clients and workmates.

Education

Web Design & Development Diploma - Digital Media & IT Sept. 2018 - April 2020 Northern Alberta Institute of Technology

- A two year program in the DMIT section that started by building a strong HTML/CSS foundation
- Built on my natural design abilities, helping me to creatively explore
- Highlighted courses included: Web Fundamentals, Javascript, Web Usability, & Visual Communications

KEY SKILLS

Front-end Development

- Built a strong knowledge of HTML/CSS, as well as a starting point in Javascript and PHP while at NAIT
- Experience in building sites using the Elementor plugin for WordPress
- Learned how to create good layouts and UI such as contrast, visual elements, and fonts
- Developed a passion for great design and user experience; taking time to plan out what the client needs out of the site, as well as users

Visual Design

- Demonstrated natural design skills & attention to detail while working through a variety of school projects and assessments
- Exercised strong artistic skills due to dedicated time to drawing and working on my own graphic novel.

- Demonstrated the ability to create appealing wireframes, logos, and other design elements in the Web Usability and Visual Communication classes and through work experience
- Developed an awareness of space, colours, and contrast when receiving feedback from instructors, classmates, and workmates on projects
- Knowledge of Adobe programs such as Photoshop and Illustrator, while taking a
 class that specifically taught us basic skills. Assignments in NAIT and in my job have
 allowed me to become very familiar with these softwares, while often looking up ways
 to do new things
- Demonstrated the ability to design vehicle wraps, price mats and brochures where a lot of content needed to be shown while maintaining visual appeal
- Drew many illustrations for the Hervey Cats Foundation that were to capture the story of future blog articles

Communication & Collaboration

- Capstone helped harness the importance of clear, respectful communication with clients and team members
- Capstone encouraged reliable and fair team work
- Exercised the ability to connect and have compassion for others
- Learned American Sign Language all three years of High School. This encouraged dedication and the desire to communicate with others
- Maintaining a respectful and collaborative relationship with my workmates and clients
- Exercised the ability to present a project or idea to a workmate or client via video conference
- Maintaining high work drive and communication with workmates while working remotely
- Used online tools such as Google Chat, Mattermost, and Freedcamp, to keep organised and up-to-date with workmates and the progression of projects

Dedication

- Dedicated my time and energy to work hard and ask for help; this made me appreciate the web industry, though I had no knowledge of it prior to NAIT
- Demonstrated a hard working attitude, willing to learn new things and ask questions when I was stuck on new topics or assignments
- Exercised strong time management skills, reliability, and conscientiousness of others when working on both individual and group projects; like Capstone
- Worked with clients to ensure they were receiving what they needed from their website and logo designs to improve their business
- Took initiative to learn new design skills through online teaching videos and practised abilities independently when incoming work was slow
- Presented an eagerness to learn and to be taught how to better improve my skills in web, design, and communication

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web & Graphic Designer - Choice Online Marketing Group

June 2020 - Present

- I take satisfaction in solving creative problems through sketches, research, to the final construction of websites or graphic design projects: logos, banners, ads, website layouts
- It is important to me to gain a clear understanding of requirements of a project to satisfy the clients and give them results that will improve their businesses
- I have responsibilities of making updates to websites, learning how to use different programs including PhotoShop, Illustrator, introductions to Figma, Elementor, WordPress, Procreate, and Visual Studio Code.

Sales Associate - Simons

June 2019 - August 2020

- I worked hard and took pride in keeping my section of the store clean and welcoming for customers
- It is important to me that customers find what they are looking for and enjoy their shopping experience. I regularly engaged with customers and colleagues, which has strengthened my communication skills
- Managed cash transactions and the opening or closing of the tills

ACHIEVEMENTS

Alexander Rutherford Scholarship

Sept. 2018

Government of Canada

Awarded the highest amount for High School Honours

Dean's Honour Roll April 2019

NAIT

Awarded recognition for a high GPA in the Winter 2019 school semester

Jason Lang Scholarship Sept. 2019

ΝΔΙΤ

Awarded for a high GPA in NAIT

Dean's Honour Roll June 2021

NAIT

Awarded recognition for a high GPA in the Winter 2020 school semester

Other

CHOICE OMG

I have received much praise by happy clients and company management for my excellent work ethic and ability to create design solutions.